Frederico Parreira

Personal Information

Date of Birth: 11/03/1998 Telephone: +55 (35)999580037
Nationality: Brazilian Email: souofred.developer@gmail.com

Address: Padre Francisco Costa, 131, Jacutinga 37590-000, Brazil

Professional Goal

Build a career in software development using as a base all my organization, communication and teamwork skills acquired in 7 years of previous experiences exploring the multidisciplinarity of other areas.

Always committed to offering the best result for the company and its projects. With advanced technical skills and the ability to work in a team, I seek challenging opportunities to apply and improve my knowledge, contributing to the growth and success of the company's projects.

Professional Experience

08/2021 - 11/2021 Monte Sião, MG, Brazil

Intern - Fullstack Developer

Conexão Informática

- Implementation of a website to consume a CRUD API using JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS3.
- Implementation of an API for registering customers, products, services and payments.
- Fixing bugs in the Node.js code of company's server.
- Storage, retrieval and manipulation of data in a database using MySQL.

04/2022 - 05/2022 Jacutinga, MG, Brazil

Fullstack Developer

Auto Mecânica Parreira (Freelance)

- Development of an application for registering customers, employees, vehicles and payments.
- Creation of middleware's with authentication in application routes using express.
- MongoDB database implementation.
- Implementation of JavaScript on the frontend and Node.js on the backend, using security practices (encryption, hash, JWT), Test-Driven Development and clean architecture.

Education

07/2018 - 11/2022 Itapira, Brazil

Computer Science | Bachelor Universidade de Ensino Superior de Itapira

I acquired a solid foundation in programming languages such as Java, C++ and C. I learned to design and develop software, databases and web-based systems using industry standard tools and techniques. In addition, I acquired knowledge in areas such as algorithms, data structures, computer networks and operating systems.

Skills

- LANGUAGES

- English Fluent
- Portuguese Native Language

- COMPETENCE

- Teamwork with diverse and dynamic team.
- Decision making and team leadership.
- · Logical reasoning.

- TECHNOLOGIES

- Experience with SQL and NoSQL.
- Experience with Node. js and Typescript.
- Experience with React.js, Next.js, JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS3/SCSS.
- Knowledge of C, C++, Java, Design Patterns and Clean Architecture.